CHRISTOPHER LACHANCE

https://ctlachance.com | https://github.com/CTLaChance | christopher.t.lachance@gmail.com | (409) 543 - 8490

Personal Summary

Software Engineer with a passion for music, minimalism, and modern design. Experienced in a wide array of creative disciplines, capable of rapidly acquiring new skills and technologies, and always ready for the next challenge. Excited to professionally transition into the web development ecosystem.

Technology Experience

Programming Languages: JavaScript ES6+, C#, TypeScript, Java, Lua, C++

Style/Markup Languages: HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, XML, Markdown

Miscellaneous: NodeJS, Svelte, React, Git, GitHub, SVN, Linux, Bash, Unity

3D, Photoshop, Virtual Reality

Professional Experience

AGS, LLC January 2018 - Present

Software Engineer

- Redesigned critical game logic to meet the demands of complex math models
- Worked collaboratively with artists, musicians, and game designers to implement their design vision without compromise
- Handled various DevOps challenges that arose from working in a small team environment
- · Lead Engineer for the following 9 games:

Pharaoh Sun
 Wild Tiki
 Bao Bei Cash
 Dragon Blast
 Shining Dragon
 Temple Cash

CACI (NASA Contractor)

May 2017 - December 2017

Software Engineer (Contract)

- Developed features and resolved issues for NASA's Trick Simulation Environment
- Integrated Trick engine simulations with the Unity 3D Game Engine to provide a visual representation of simulation objects
- · Significantly refactored the Trick documentation to improve readability and user experience

Algebra Readiness Educators, LLC

June 2011 - Present

Web Developer and Graphic Designer

- Designed and implemented the company website
 - Responsible for a 10 fold increase in total book sales
 - Now the primary venue through which purchase orders are submitted
- Designed book covers for 12+ mathematical workbooks
- · Created business cards, booth displays, postcards, t-shirts, and other marketing materials

Education

B.S. Computer Science December 2016
Lamar University Beaumont, TX
Mirabeau Scholar 3.792 Major GPA